How to add details to your outfit
Next, we are going to add some details to our outfit.
First, we are going to apply the right fabric to our outfit to make it look more realistic.
Go to the object window and find the plant label.
Select the default fabric, and its properties will appear at the bottom.
A plant has two parts.
The first part is the fabric, and the second part is the physical properties.
First, let's see how to modify the fabric part.
Click on the color block, open the color panel, and select the color you want to modify according to your needs.
You can also click on the browser icon next to the pattern.
Double-click on the appropriate picture on your computer to load it as a fabric pattern.
After loading the pattern, you can set the size of the band at the bottom of the conversion settings.
In addition to manually inputting data,
you can also view the pattern of the fabric by clicking on the pattern tool.
Select a pattern, click and drag the axis of the ball in the upper right corner to view the pattern along the selected direction.
You can load other patterns according to your needs, and set the corresponding settings.
You can also click on the production icon next to the pattern to generate the corresponding material pattern.
After loading or generating the pattern, you can set its corresponding properties at the bottom.
For example, you can set the strength of the pattern.
You can continue to load or generate other patterns according to your needs.
After setting the material, you can adjust the physical properties at the bottom.
You can select the physical properties of the pre-set fabric we have provided for you.
In addition to manually setting various properties,
you can click on the pattern button in the upper left corner of the input column to go to the fabric library in the pattern library.
For the fabric assets built into the software,
you can view the preview here.
According to the fabric placed on the small ball,
this is the texture, and select the fabric you like.
Drag the fabric to the original fabric, and you can replace the original fabric.
Please select a piece of fabric according to your preference.
We can apply different fabrics for different versions,
so we need to select another fabric as a pocket fabric.
Drag the fabric to the input column,
you can add a new fabric.
Click and drag the new fabric to the pocket fabric,
it will apply a new fabric for the pocket fabric.
Open the model,
you can see that the fabric has been applied to the new fabric,
because the physical properties have changed,
the texture has changed.
In addition to the physical properties that will affect the calculation effect,
we also need to make other adjustments to the fabric and the virtual model,
to make the clothing more real.
First, open the display frame,
and look more clearly at the grid layout.
Next, select all clothing versions,
and reduce the particle diameter to 10.
The particle diameter is the distance between the grid points,
the smaller the number, the smaller the grid, the more the number.
In order to make it easier to see the clothing fold,
close the display frame,
press the control key to start the simulation,
and then press the control key to stop the simulation.
You can see that due to the increase in the grid surface,
the fold of the version becomes softer,
and the details will be richer.
Select all versions again,
and reduce the particle diameter to 1.
Open the simulation,
you can see that the clothing is closer to the virtual model.
This option is set to the air thickness around the version.
By adjusting this value,
you can reduce the distance between the version and the version or the virtual model.
You can also choose the virtual model,
and reduce the surface diameter of the virtual model.
The surface diameter is the air thickness around the virtual model,
similar to the method and the impact thickness.
These two values should not be set too low,
otherwise it may cause excessive collision and instability due to the peak.
After adjusting the clothing simulation,
we can also add some details to the clothing.
First is the line.
Through the line,
you can add some line effects to the clothing.
Select the line line tool,
click the line,
you can create a line near the line,
and add creation details.
After creating,
you can see the generated line effect in the 3D window.
The line tool and the sewing line tool are very similar.
Here we choose the line effect in the free line creation pocket.
Then go to the object window,
you can select the line tool,
and automatically switch to the line icon.
Select a line type,
in the attribute editor,
you can also adjust its properties.
For example, the pattern of the line,
you can change the color pattern according to your need.
You can see that the line of the line has been modified to the left-hand style.
The bottom can set the thickness of the line,
the length,
the diameter,
and the material properties.
You can try to adjust these properties according to your needs.
In addition,
you can also click the button,
select the appropriate OBJ file,
and register it as a line pattern.
Or go to the drawing window of the line,
and select more complex lines.
After loading the line,
we can also add a copy according to our needs.
Click the copy label of the drawing window,
click the icon in the upper left corner of the copy tab,
open the copy tab,
and select the butterfly node in the left-hand category.
Double-click to load a butterfly node.
Drag the butterfly node to the 3D window,
you can load the butterfly node copy.
You can use the position tool to adjust the position of the copy.
Click the center of the copy,
then click the water icon,
then click the front and middle of the collar.
The butterfly node will be fixed in the position of the click.
Then we can go to the attribute editor,
adjust the size and weight of the copy.
Set the copy weight to be smaller.
Open the simulation,
you can see that the weight of the copy will be used in the place of the copy.
After selecting the copy,
click the transform icon in the upper right corner of the positioning ball,
and switch to the find positioning ball.
You can find the copy by dragging the axis according to your needs.
This is the tutorial on adding details.
Thank you for watching, see you in the next video.
Subtitles by the Amara.org community